wijmo.com 2019-07-19

# Privacy Policy | GrapeCity

## GrapeCity, Inc., Privacy Statement

This website is maintained by GrapeCity, Inc. ("GrapeCity"), 201 S. Highland Avenue, 3rd Floor, Pittsburgh, PA 15206, USA. By accessing or using this site, you agree to the terms of the GrapeCity Online Privacy Policy, as outlined below. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not access or use this site. As of May 25th, 2018, GrapeCity has updated its Privacy Policy which is published herewith in order to give you a better understanding of this important Policy as well as the company’s business Practices and adherence to the (EU) General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). If you have any questions or concerns, please contact our Data Protection Officer at [us.dpo@grapecity.com](mailto:us.dpo@grapecity.com).

GrapeCity has established this Online Privacy Policy to help you understand how we intend to treat your Personal Information.  
This policy applies to information we collect on our Website(s) and through the use of our products if/when you sign up for an account in email, text, and other electronic messages between you and our website(s), including our technical support.

## Commitment to Privacy

We at GrapeCity are committed to respecting your online privacy and recognize the need for appropriate protection and management of the personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") you share with us. Personal Information includes any information that may be used to identify you, such as: first and last name, home or other physical address, telephone numbers, e-mail addresses, or other contact information that is provided to us by you, or any other party. In general, you may visit GrapeCity's Web pages without disclosing to us who you are and without revealing any Personal Information about yourself. You should be aware that if you choose to provide us with your Personal Information, we may transfer such information, within GrapeCity or to GrapeCity's third-party service providers, across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world, subject to the limitations of this Privacy Policy. GrapeCity strives to comply with all applicable laws around the globe that are designed to protect your privacy. Although legal requirements may vary from country to country, GrapeCity intends to adhere to the principles set forth in this Online Privacy Policy.

## The data we collect

When you visit the GrapeCity website ([www.grapecity.com]()) you have the opportunity to download a trial of our software and/or create an account (a one-time process), through which process you provide us with information that identifies you when you return. From the time that you create an account, we are the ‘Controller’ of the personal data you provide to us. In this process, we only collect basic personal data about you that includes some or all of your name, organization, job title, address, email address, IP address, telephone number, contact history, order history, information selection choices, and product usage information from GrapeCity and/or our Technology Partners. It also includes information you provide to us (whether requested by us or not) in emails, on the telephone, in voicemails and in computer chats, and a record of sign-ins to your GrapeCity account.

If you choose not to create an account or download a trial version of our software, we will not have collected any of your personal data, but you will still be able to use many of the information features of our website that do not require registration.

## Why we collect this information

We collect your basic personal data so that we can better operate our business systems, to ensure a better user experience when you interact with us, and to gain the ability to provide you with better product and business information. We do not collect any personal data from you that we do not need, and we keep all personal data collected confidential. Additionally, through our registration process, we will seek your permission first for the right to use any of your personal data, such as for email communications, marketing, or delivery of complimentary promotional items.

Registration provides unlimited access to our website, and when you sign in to your GrapeCity account, you can amend your personal details, enjoy an efficient user experience on our website, access product information and request trials, create your own quotations, establish payment mechanisms, receive product upgrades, information on new releases, product selection assistance, receive special offers, and enable other features designed to further improve your experience.

We are the developers/publishers of the software products that we sell. When you purchase software products, your name, organization, street address, and email address are registered with us in order to identify you as a legitimate licensee. This also ensures that you receive the latest software product version to download and install, and in addition, that you receive, or are offered, the latest software updates, maintenance and support.

## How we use the data collected

All the personal data processing do is carried out by our employees or by third parties contracted by us for this purpose. All such third parties are contractually obligated by us to adhere to the principles embodied in this privacy statement.

We use your personal data to communicate with you about your account, product updates and information, to improve your user experience, and other related reasons.

GrapeCity has a Data Protection Officer in place to oversee the effective, secure, and confidential processing of your personal data. To request more information about our Data Protection Process, please contact our Data Protection Officer at [us.dpo@grapecity.com](mailto:us.dpo@grapecity.com).

If you have created an account or download a trial of our software, you can amend or update your preferences on your GrapeCity Account here.

## How long we keep your data

We are required by tax law to keep your basic personal data (name, address, contact details) for a minimum of 7 years following your most recent purchase, after which time you may request that it be destroyed. However, if you have purchased any perpetual product licenses, your personal data will be kept indefinitely. Our licensing records and certain identification metadata used by our anti-fraud systems will also be maintained indefinitely.

## Additional data usage

We would also like to use your name and email address to inform you of future offers, product developments, and new products we think may be of interest to you based on your previous enquiries and orders. This information is not shared with third parties and you can unsubscribe at any time via phone, email or our website.

## GrapeCity Cookie Policy

GrapeCity and some of our third-party service suppliers use cookies (small text files placed on your device) and similar technologies to enable effective provision of our website and online services and to help collect usage and performance data. Cookies allow us to help us recognize you when you return, store your preferences and settings, enable you to sign-in, combat fraud, and analyze how our website and online services are performing. We also use cookies for other purposes, outlined in the GrapeCity Cookies section of this policy. Our website may include cookies and similar technologies from third-party service providers.

You have a variety of tools to control cookies and similar technologies, including browser controls, to block and delete cookies and controls from some third-party analytics service providers to opt out of data collection. Your browser and other choices may affect your experiences with our website.

## How to control and delete cookies

If you wish to restrict or block the cookies that are set by the GrapeCity website(s), you can do so through your browser settings.

Please be aware that restricting cookies may affect on the functionality of the GrapeCity website(s), such as signing in, managing your account, or purchasing products.

GrapeCity uses a small number of suppliers who also set cookies on the GrapeCity website(s) on our behalf. Details are outlined below.

## GrapeCity Cookies

This is a list of the cookies set by the GrapeCity website(s) and their purposes.

## Website Performance

  1. Google Analytics: Web traffic and anonymous site activity recording. Held for 24 months. More information [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245) and [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=us).
  2. Watson Web Tracking: Web traffic and user activity recording. More information [here](https://www.ibm.com/watson/data-privacy/).

## Third Party/Social

  1. Adroll: Web traffic and retargeting opportunities. More information [here](https://help.adroll.com/hc/en-us/articles/216104687-Privacy-Notice-Requirements).
  2. Bing tracking: Web traffic and conversion tools. More information [here](https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/privacy-and-data-protection-policies).
  3. Facebook: Social media integration and retargeting opportunities. More information [here](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php).
  4. LinkedIn: Social media integration and conversion tools. More information [here](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/sas-terms).
  5. Twitter: Social media integration and conversion tools. More information [here](https://business.twitter.comhelp/troubleshooting/how-twitter-ads-work.html).

## Choice not to provide data

You may choose whether or not to provide Personal Information to GrapeCity. However, when you engage in certain activities on this site, such as ordering products, downloading software, or entering contests, GrapeCity requires that you provide certain information about yourself by filling out and submitting an online form. It is entirely optional for you to engage in these activities. If you elect to engage in these activities, GrapeCity may require that you provide certain personal information, such as your name, mailing address, e-mail address, and other personal identifying information.

## Data Security

Wherever your Personal Information may be held by GrapeCity or by a third party on GrapeCity’s behalf, reasonable and appropriate precautions, such as encryption, firewalls and like technologies, are and will be implemented to protect such Personal Information from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access.

## Access/Accuracy

To the extent that you do provide us with Personal Information, GrapeCity wishes to maintain it accurately and keep it up to date. When we collect Personal Information from you, our goal is to provide a means of contacting GrapeCity should you need to access, update or correct that information. If, for any reason, you desire to review such information, please contact our Data Protection Officer at [us.dpo@grapecity.com](mailto:us.dpo@grapecity.com) and we will make reasonable efforts to promptly provide you with such information. You have the right to request that we remove all of your User Data. We cannot delete your User Data except by deleting your user account and revoking your licenses, and we will only delete your account when we no longer have a lawful basis for processing your User Data or after a final determination that your User Data was unlawfully processed.

If we believe the deletion would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect, we may not remove your User Data. In all other cases, we will retain your User Data as set forth in this policy. In addition, we cannot completely delete your User Data if the data exists in previous backups. We also cannot delete your forum posts, but proper access and use of information provided on the Websites, including forum posts, is governed by our Terms and Conditions.

## Third Party Data Usage

Your personal information will not be leased, sold, rented, or otherwise made available to any other third party except to the extent necessary to comply with applicable laws, police investigations, or in legal proceedings where such information is relevant. Occasionally, GrapeCity allows access to database information to bonded mailing houses only for the purpose of allowing for the printing of mailing labels that are used for GrapeCity's own direct mail and promotional purposes. In those instances, the third party is strictly bound by these terms.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, you hereby agree that GrapeCity may assign, sell, license, or otherwise transfer to a third party, your name, address, email address, member name, and any other personal information in connection with an assignment, sale, joint venture, or other transfer or disposition of a material portion or essentially all of the assets or stock of GrapeCity or its affiliated entities.

## Children's Privacy

This website is not designed nor structured to attract children. Accordingly, we do not intend to collect Personal Information from anyone we know to be under 13 years of age. If we are made aware that information is or has been submitted by or collected from a child under the age of thirteen, we will promptly delete this information.

## Collection of Sensitive Information

We do not collect Sensitive Information such as medical, health, racial, ethnic, political, religious, philosophic, union membership, or sexual orientation information. If we are made aware that we have received such information, we will promptly proceed to its deletion.

## Your Consent

By using this Web site, you consent to the terms of our Online Privacy Policy and to GrapeCity's processing of Personal Information for the purposes outlined above. Should the Online Privacy Policy change, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that these changes are brought to your attention by posting all changes prominently on our website for a reasonable period of time.

GrapeCity is not responsible for the privacy or security practices of our customers, which may differ from those set out in this privacy statement.
